There will be organizational beams.
Inside, these beams here relate to the small wing here.
Beams here.
You see, these are very important lines of force.
But at the moment you have primitive cephalic flexion,
you will have the sub-mesencephalic mesenchyme
compressed between the anterior part of the brain vesicle
and the posterior brain vesicle.
This is at the beginning.
My tissue is like this.
And through the flexion movement,
I move forward.
The mesenchyme below,
will undergo a compression field on its axis,
It will lose water,
it will densify and it becomes
cartilaginous tissue.
This is how the base of the skull forms.
Through the flexion movement.
With as an axis, always,
my notochord.
And on either side,
I have what we call at the top the ethmoid, just below
the body of the sphenoid,
below that the basilar part of the occipital bone,
and especially here what we call the wings of the sphenoid,
but also the point where the eye will settle.
It's the support of the eye, the sphenoid.
The sphenoid is very important for the stability of the eye.
As it grows, the mesenchyme...
that is above, the bony capsule
of the eye,
will develop through the growth
of the brain, around the eye.
So the eye
is there, it follows
the movement, it is conforming
and conformed,
and the bony tissue
comes to encase around it, comes to close
with specific lines of force
that support
the support of the eye. This means that the eye
can destabilize the skull
or the skull can destabilize the eye.
You see?
A small bump, a little fringe
can completely destabilize the orbit
and completely destabilize
the reflection, you see?
So it's really important to arrive
at re-stabilizing the eye, to understand it
both by the brain and by
the skull. This is your nose.
It's going to grow.
Bam! And there, we see the eye
appearing on the side. And you see,
at the same time, I have the palate system
forming. At the moment I have
my eye forming,
my palate is coming into place.
You see?
Really with the closure. The palatine,
here, comes in. And when I have
completely my eye having found its
axis in its verticality,
in its horizontality,
I have the palate formed.
So it is really the point
terminal
very important on the bony level that is forming.
It's a first convergence.
So we see here, you see, the growth, the importance of this growth.
And look at the cephalic part.
It is at the moment when this cephalic part will really begin to grow
that the eyes come closer to the midline.
Look carefully, with a support point that will form at the level of the Nasion.
Look now at the white part.
I am growing.
Now, I explode.
The eyes come back toward the midline.
Did you see?
We see again this biodynamics
or this morphogenetics of development.
This huge growth
that comes from here.
that makes my eyes come to the center.
The cortical development directs the eye in its position.
You will have two spirals.
One spiral of the eye
and one counter-spiral of bone.
You see this in the shape of the sutures.
If you look closely, you need to study the orientation of this suture.
And you see that this premaxilla is three-dimensional.
You see, it does this.
You see, it goes up, it goes down, and it goes back up.
And it really creates a three-dimensionality.
And well, you see that it forms, this shape, orbital, ocular.